<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sater Group</title>
    <description>The Sater Group has been designing custom homes for over 35 years, Dan Sater is an award winning home designer.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:11:01 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 13:11:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Preliminary Design Process</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So we have selected our home site, the perfect team, established realistic expectations and from that created our wish list. Now we are ready to start the preliminary design process. The preliminary design process is critical to the success of the home’s design and function so it should not be rushed. You and your design professional need to work closely so that they understand your expectations completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also make sure your design professional has researched and understands all zoning requirements. Including code restrictions as well as any community guidelines that may limit or restrict the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found that for myself and my clients it is best to begin sketching the initial floor plan together. This way I can get instant feedback about relationships of rooms to one another. When creating the prelims one has to think of the entirety of the design including the exterior appearance. Usually at the end of a two to three hour session we walk away with a rough concept of the desired floor plan and sometimes even the elevation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then take the sketch and refine it for presentation to client. This is a time when I encourage the client to spend time studying and reviewing the floor plan. More or less getting acquainted with it as this home will be a constant companion for many years so it needs to be well suited to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important consideration for the design is how well it fits the site. Does it take advantage of views, avoid undesirable views (i.e.: neighboring homes, power poles, etc.) and address the street properly. We always show the preliminary floor plan on the actual site plan to get an understanding of its relationship to it. Evaluating proper room size is a critical task. Either working with your designer or an interior designer to look at furniture placement in each room to ensure the room functions as desired. Will that dining room accommodate a table for 10 people? Can two full sized beds fit on that wall? Etc…
Refining the Preliminary Design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve arrived at a satisfactory floor plan, we can now work to refine the exterior elevation. Creating the front elevation is the icing on the cake. Most clients have difficulty reading a two dimensional rendering. Trust in your designer is important. Your design professional may employ three dimensional modeling which can be very beneficial in understanding the actual home better. I am still a dinosaur and create designs on paper. However we have offered clients the ability to have an outside source create a perspective rendering to help them reach a comfort level with the actual design. Nothing can be worse than to find that you are less than thrilled with your new home’s exterior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve finalized the preliminary design process you can talk with your builder to get rough estimates of building costs before moving into working drawings. You may need to get preliminary approval from your Architectural Review Board (ARB) if you live in a planned community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proper planning can ensure a successful and rewarding home building experience for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the fifth blog in a nine part series entitled “Custom Home Design’s Rewards and Challenges”. Dan F Sater II FAIBD/CGP is an award winning and internationally recognized residential designer. He has designed tens of thousands of homes and received over 500 awards in his thirty-five year career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/09/the-preliminary-design-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/08/09/the-preliminary-design-process.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wishlist For Your Custom Designed Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a custom home is a daunting task, but it can be very rewarding with proper planning, preparation, wise choices and &lt;strong&gt;realistic expectations&lt;/strong&gt;. This article will deal with planning and preparation and it starts with a wishlist.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughtful itemization of each space and desired features is critical in effectively communicating to your design professional(s). It’s also important to have a discussion with them about the way you live and use your home. For example, do you like to entertain, cook, play games, read, etc.? Creating a home that fits your lifestyle is more important than the right collection of rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in our previous article, it is important to set realistic goals. One must consider your wishlist as it compares to your budget. I once had a client that wanted a list of spaces that would have been over 12,000 square feet and over $3 million to build. However their square footage requirement was 9,000 square feet and had a budget of $1.5 million. I responded by asking which house did they want to build? The 12,000, the 9,000 or the 5,000 square foot one they budgeted for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custom-designed-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wishlist for your custom home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was once asked by a publisher to write a book titled “The Smaller Home”. I responded by saying “&lt;em&gt;are you sure you have the right designer?&lt;/em&gt;” Our firm is mostly known for our luxury home designs. In that book I dealt with this issue in detail, even creating a wishlist template. It is important to prioritize each item, as your wishlist, budget and final cost to build often conflict. While that theater room may be nice, how important is that feature? Another part of the equation is honestly evaluating how often you would use that feature. We have done many home theaters, for example, and have found after the newness wears off, these room are seldomly used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-wishlist-can-be-time-sensitive&quot;&gt;The Wishlist can be Time Sensitive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor to consider is the longevity of use for a particular room or feature. We have created bedrooms for an infant near the Master Bedroom. By the time planning, permitting and construction are completed the child’s use of that space is no longer needed. They have matured in the process and no longer need to be right next to the parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you list rooms and sizes, think more in terms of how many people you want to seat or accommodate This is more effective than deciding on a certain room size that may or may not accomplish the desired need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another proactive step is to list things you do not like in a home. I once had a client that gave me more stated dislikes than likes. This further helps your design professional in crafting your home design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the more thought and detail invested into creating your wish list, the better your initial preliminary design results will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth blog in a nine part series entitled “Custom Home Design’s Rewards and Challenges”. Dan F Sater II FAIBD/CGP is an award winning and internationally recognized residential designer. He has designed tens of thousands of homes and received over 500 awards in his thirty-five year career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 17:19:53 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/08/making-home-wishlist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/08/08/making-home-wishlist.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Caribbean Custom Home Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custom-caribbean.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;more caribbean construction&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new Caribbean custom home design by The Sater Group is taking shape on a tropical Caribbean Island for it’s new owners. Designed in a contemporary British West Indies theme, this Caribbean custom home features a main house with a detached garage and guest house. It is being built entirely in masonry construction to resist harsh tropical climate and give owners maintenance free living. It is incorporating many energy efficient features as well. Dan Sater II FAIBD, CPBD, CGP has been designing homes internationally for many years, many of which are in the Caribbean. This Caribbean custom home employs many of same construction features found in Dan’s native southwest Florida home designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-take-seriously-our-commitment-to-clients&quot;&gt;We take seriously our commitment to Clients&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with clients in many locales has it’s challenges. We at The Sater Group take seriously the task of translating each client’s wishes and dreams into realities. We also guide and inform clients of opportunities and potential issues as we work through each step of the design process. Our vast experience in creating homes in so many different countries and climates can be used for our client’s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custom-caribbean-construction-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;custom caribbean&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;let-us-help-you-in-your-next-project&quot;&gt;Let us Help You in Your next Project….&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to talk and/or meet with you to discuss your next custom home design, wherever that may be. Let our experience work for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custom-caribbean-construction-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Main house with guest house&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;caribbean-custom-home-not-your-cup-of-tea&quot;&gt;Caribbean Custom Home not Your Cup of tea?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for something different, Dan has a very large &lt;a href=&quot;https://saterdesign.com&quot;&gt;stock home plan collection&lt;/a&gt;. Take a moment to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://saterdesign.com&quot;&gt;Sater Design Collection&lt;/a&gt; and see what over &lt;em&gt;30&lt;/em&gt; years of award winning home design can offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 12:16:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/12/caribbean-custom-home-progress.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/12/caribbean-custom-home-progress.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Realistic Expectations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating Realistic Expectations for your new home building project can save you a lot of time, energy and heartache. This is one of the most problematic issues I have encountered in my 35 years of home design. There are three major areas where most clients make false assumptions that can hamper a successful design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;friends-and-family-connection&quot;&gt;Friends and Family Connection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If only I had a dollar for every time I heard the phrase “ Yes, but we have an Uncle that does &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;_”. While many of us may know someone related to construction, it is unrealistic to assume this connection will yield double digit percentage savings. In fact unless you are building as an owner/builder utilizing a special connection may even be frowned upon your builder as it may cause more trouble than it’s worth to him. Being an owner/builder also yields many difficulties that I will detail more in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a friend or family member may cost you more than any imagined savings as their handling of a job as a favor can mean time delays and costs for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-you-really-smarter-than-an-8th-grader&quot;&gt;Are you really Smarter than an 8th Grader&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all naturally imagine we are smarter than the next person. I wish this was actually true. If every contractor and design professional you meet with tells you typical costs per square foot are &lt;strong&gt;$200&lt;/strong&gt;, why would you still talk about a &lt;strong&gt;$150&lt;/strong&gt; per square foot budget as attainable? Failing to come to terms with prevalent costs and your actual budget can be extremely painful. I have worked with many clients that failed to do this. They ended up six months down the road with house plans that are useless to them and countless hours expended by their contractor and his/her sub-contractors for a pointless exercise. Please don’t make this mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eyes-are-too-big-for-the-stomach&quot;&gt;Eyes are too big for the Stomach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to the other mistakes, setting a realistic program and budget are essential to a successful home design effort. I once had clients that had put together an extensive list of rooms and features they wanted for their new home. Their list included six bedrooms, game room, theater room and much more. Their list from my experience dictated a home of over ten thousand square feet yet their desired square footage was less than eight thousand. Better sill, their budget wouldn’t build a six thousand square foot home. I asked them “ Which home do you want to build?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When putting together your wish list, critically analyze how essential each space is and how it fits within your budget. Always keep in mind that consumers typically see their home costs go another ten percent above their original contract amount. Will you really use that dedicated theater room or will it simply become a rarely used extravagance? Do I really need a Great Room to seat ten people when that need may only occur a few times a year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting realistic and achieve able goals in building your next dream home can save you from unnecessary frustration and cost. Not to mention countless hours and months of time chasing a rabbit that isn’t real. Designing and building a new custom home can be a rewarding and even fun experience if you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the third article in a nine part series entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;https://satergroup.com/news/2015/06/09/custom-home-designs-rewards-challenges.html&quot;&gt;Custom home design’s rewards and challenges&lt;/a&gt;”. For more information on avoiding cost overruns, review this &lt;a href=&quot;http://buildingadvisor.com/estimating-errors/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 15:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/08/11/creating-realistic-expectations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/08/11/creating-realistic-expectations.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sater Group Wins Auroa Award</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aurora_award-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aurora Awards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aurora Awards we represented at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sebcshow.com/&quot;&gt;Southeast Builders Conference&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;SEBC&lt;/strong&gt;) Black Tie Gala event at the Rosen Center in Orlando, FL on July 18. The Award competition recognizes achievements in building design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aurora Awards is a competitive award competition held during &lt;a href=&quot;http://sebcshow.com/&quot;&gt;Southeast Builders Conference&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;SEBC&lt;/strong&gt;). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fhba.com/&quot;&gt;Florida Home Builders Association&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;FHBA&lt;/strong&gt;) sponsors the Award competition; one of the largest associations of it’s kind. The Aurora Award design competition is presented to outstanding builders, planners, architects, developers, designers, and interior merchandisers within a twelve state southeastern and eastern Caribbean region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design competition since it’s inception thirty-five years ago, continues to grow and honor residential and commercial designers and builders in 135 categories. Categories consist of Commercial, Residential, Price Point, Energy Efficiency, Green Building, Merchandising, Interior Design and many more. The winners in the categories also recognize major team members that contributed on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Aurora Award can be awarded to one entrant in each of the 135 categories. In addition to the 135 categories there are Grand Aurora Awards based on sub categories and one (this year there was a tie) Golden Aurora Award for the whole Award competition. For a complete list of all Award winners please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.TheAuroras.com&quot;&gt;The Auroras website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;below-are-the-awards-our-company-won-at-this-years-event&quot;&gt;Below are the awards our company won at this year’s event.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2015-grand-aurora-award-best-of-state-louisiana&quot;&gt;2015 Grand Aurora Award Best of State: Louisiana&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CUSTOM HOMES - &lt;strong&gt;Over $3,000,001&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Sater Group&lt;br /&gt;
Maenza&lt;br /&gt;
Mandeville, LA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/meanza-home-mobile-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Maenza Residence - Winner of 2015 Grand Aurora Award for Best in State&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Maenza-First-Floor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First Floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Maenza-Second-Floor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Second Floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;detached-single-family-home---750001---1000000&quot;&gt;Detached Single-Family Home - $750,001 - $1,000,000&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sater Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://saterdesign.com/product/prairie-pine-court/&quot;&gt;Prairie Pine Court&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fort Myers, FL&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://saterdesign.com/product/prairie-pine-court/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/prairie-pine-road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prairie Pine Court&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://saterdesign.com/product/prairie-pine-court/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/7083_M.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prairie Pine Court floor plan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;for-over-thirty-years-the-sater-groups-innovative-approach-to-custom-luxury-home-design-has-attended-to-the-reality-of-its-clients-dreams&quot;&gt;For over thirty years, the Sater Group’s innovative approach to custom luxury home design has attended to the reality of its client’s dreams.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design, creativity and dedication to excellence of Dan F. Sater II, FAIBD, has earned the Sater Group recognition as one of the foremost professional residential design firms in the country. The Sater Group’s innovative approach to custom home design has resulted in over &lt;strong&gt;500&lt;/strong&gt; national design awards, as well as a multitude of international design commissions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 16:34:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/30/sater-group-wins-aurora-awards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/30/sater-group-wins-aurora-awards.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Luxury Model Home Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Miromar-Lake-Model.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Luxury Model Home designed by the Sater Group&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new luxury model home design by the Sater Group is nearing completion with a fall start anticipated! Designed for the exclusive “Sorrento” enclave in Miromar Lakes subdivision in Lee County, this home is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randall-mitchell.com/&quot;&gt;Randall-Mitchell Companies&lt;/a&gt; first model home there. With over 4500 living area the home boasts of many luxury features. The great room layout takes the fullest advantage of views to the expansive lake-views. The home features four bedrooms and five full and two half baths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;miromar-lakes-community&quot;&gt;Miromar Lakes Community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miromar Lakes Beach &amp;amp; Golf Club is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/71.html&quot;&gt;#1 Community in the United States and #1 Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt;; awarded the Gold Awards for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/96.html&quot;&gt;Community of the Year&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/68.html&quot;&gt;Best Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; by the National Association of Home Builders. The only Florida community to receive these building industry top honors. This is the only community to offer beaches, waterfront living and golf all within one community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-luxury-model-home-design&quot;&gt;New Luxury Model Home Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Fonteneau” Model features modern styling with broadly cantilevered hipped rooflines and crisp stucco detailing. The roof is clad in a charcoal standing seam metal. It will feature &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andersenwindows.com&quot;&gt;Andersen Windows&lt;/a&gt; new black finished window frames and the latest in impact resistance and energy efficiency. Outdoor living is the major emphasis with this home as most rooms look out to the lake beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-hope-you-will-visit-our-new-luxury-model-home-design-once-it-is-finished-for-the-2017-season&quot;&gt;We hope you will visit our new luxury model home design once it is finished for the 2017 season.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Miromar-Lake-Model.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Luxury Model Home designed by the Sater Group&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new luxury model home design by the Sater Group is nearing completion with a fall start anticipated. Designed for the exclusive “Sorrento” enclave in Miromar Lakes subdivision in Lee County, this home is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randall-mitchell.com/&quot;&gt;Randall-Mitchell Companies&lt;/a&gt; first model home there. With over 4500 living area the home boasts of many luxury features. The great room layout takes the fullest advantage of views to the expansive lake-views. The home features four bedrooms and five full and two half baths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;miromar-lakes-community-1&quot;&gt;Miromar Lakes Community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miromar Lakes Beach &amp;amp; Golf Club is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/71.html&quot;&gt;#1 Community in the United States and #1 Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt;; awarded the Gold Awards for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/96.html&quot;&gt;Community of the Year&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miromarlakes.com/news/category2/68.html&quot;&gt;Best Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; by the National Association of Home Builders. The only Florida community to receive these building industry top honors. This is the only community to offer beaches, waterfront living and golf all within one community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-luxury-model-home-design-1&quot;&gt;New Luxury Model Home Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Fonteneau” Model features modern styling with broadly cantilevered hipped rooflines and crisp stucco detailing. The roof is clad in a charcoal standing seam metal. It will feature &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andersenwindows.com&quot;&gt;Andersen Windows&lt;/a&gt; new black finished window frames and the latest in impact resistance and energy efficiency. Outdoor living is the major emphasis with this home as most rooms look out to the lake beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you will visit our new luxury model home design once it is finished for the 2017 season.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 20:18:10 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/29/new-luxury-home-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/29/new-luxury-home-design.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selecting the Ideal Home Design Team</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Interior-design-elements-sater-group.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ideal Home Design Team, Great Room photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;selecting-the-right-team-for-home-design&quot;&gt;Selecting the Right Team for Home Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as important as selecting the right site is selecting the Ideal Home Design Team. Securing the proper building designer, building contractor, interior designer and landscape architect/designer are critical to ensuring a well built custom luxury home. Each principal plays a vital role in the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;home-design-professional&quot;&gt;Home Design Professional&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In selecting the ideal home design team, the building designer is critical in helping you assess the site and your needs to see if the two are compatible. They can take your wishlist and ideas and craft them into a home that takes full advantage of your site and its challenges. In interviewing candidates make sure you feel a chemistry with them and that they are attuned and concerned with your needs. Check their references to see how past clients felt about their experience. Selecting a designer that is either a licensed architect or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aibd.org&quot;&gt;certified professional building designer&lt;/a&gt; can give you confidence as to their knowledge and/or ability. They can usually assist you in selecting some of the other team members as well. Remember price alone should not be a sole determinant in selecting this person. They can add value far beyond their fees if they are accomplished design professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;home-builder&quot;&gt;Home Builder&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building contractor is another critical part of the team. Their knowledge and experience can be indispensable to ensuring a well built home and a smooth build process. In addition to the same interview questions in selecting a building designer, make sure their background is compatible with the type and style of home you are building. For example a builder that builds mostly tract homes may not be a candidate for your new luxury custom home. Make sure they are team players and enjoy working with other team members. They should desire to create for you the best possible home and not simply the most convenient process for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interior-designer&quot;&gt;Interior Designer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interior designer is another important team member. There should definitely be a good chemistry between yourself and this professional. You will have to work extremely close with this professional as you evaluate and design the home’s character and fit to your lifestyle and tastes. They are important in evaluating the home’s schematic design and whether it will accommodate your furniture and needs. For this reason they should be brought on at least before you finalize your preliminary floor plan. It is much easier to adjust a wall length or window placement in this stage of the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;landscape-architectdesigner&quot;&gt;Landscape Architect/Designer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landscape architect or designer is another important part of the team. They provide so much more than simply plant selections. We utilize landscape architects to design driveways, pools/spas, patios, outdoor fireplaces, trellises and so much more. I always think of their contribution as the gown for the bride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-team-members&quot;&gt;Other Team Members&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other team players to consider are lighting designers, A/V designers, structural and mechanical engineers. Proper allowance and consideration for each of these disciplines can make the final product even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, selecting the ideal home design team can make the difference between satisfaction and heartbreak in the biggest undertaking of most of our lives…building a new custom home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/20/selecting-the-ideal-home-design-team.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/20/selecting-the-ideal-home-design-team.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selecting The Perfect Site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/sellecting-the-perfect-home-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Perfect Sitefor your new custom designed home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-the-first-blog-in-a-series-relating-to-the-challenges-and-opportunities-in-building-a-new-custom-home&quot;&gt;This is the first blog in a series relating to the challenges and opportunities in building a new custom home.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many consumers are leery of designing and building a custom home and for many good reasons. As a professional building designer for over &lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt; years I have seen firsthand the benefits as well as the pitfalls experienced in the process. It doesn’t matter whether you have built a home before or where it is being built. These problems are almost universal. I will be posting a series of blogs to highlight the ups and downs as well as how to make the home design endeavor an enjoyable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;find-the-perfect-site&quot;&gt;Find The Perfect Site!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home’s site is the first and most critical decision in the home building process. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.franklloydwright.org/&quot;&gt;Frank Lloyd Wright&lt;/a&gt; said about selecting a site &lt;em&gt;“Go to the very edge of town and then drive another seven miles further”&lt;/em&gt;. A great number of factors need to be considered. If you work, your commute time is a big factor. Do you want acreage or amenities? Does privacy outweigh being in a deed restricted community?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have settled on a particular site you will need to do a lot of research. If it is unimproved land, are there utilities nearby? What is the zoning restrictions (&lt;em&gt;if any&lt;/em&gt;) to building on the property? Will you need a well, septic system? Please remember, large unimproved sites will have much greater infrastructure costs associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cant-build-on-the-perfect-site&quot;&gt;Can’t Build on The Perfect Site?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose a lot in a deed restricted community, make sure you understand those restrictions before purchasing. Don’t be surprised when you can’t build that contemporary home because the community guidelines call for an exclusively Colonial style. Are there minimum square footage requirements that may force you to build a larger home than you want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work with many clients that become frustrated dealing with the restrictions of their community and their &lt;strong&gt;ARB&lt;/strong&gt; or “&lt;strong&gt;Architectural Review Board&lt;/strong&gt;”. However remember this process is intended to protect both yourself and your neighbor’s investment. If individual expression is your passion, you had better think twice about a deed restricted community.&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other considerations are governmental restrictions. Building setbacks; minimum floor elevation; height, use and coverage restrictions should be carefully examined by you and your design professional or builder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you consider carefully your home site and its limitations upfront you are well on your way to an enjoyable building experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;next-issue-selecting-the-perfect-team&quot;&gt;Next Issue: Selecting The Perfect Team&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/13/selecting-the-perfect-site.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/07/13/selecting-the-perfect-site.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Custom Home Design's Rewards and Challenges</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custom-home-design-challenges.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prairie Pine Court and Custom Home Design Process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;custom-home-designs-rewards-and-challenges-will-be-spotlighted-in-this-series-of-blog-posts&quot;&gt;Custom home design’s rewards and challenges will be spotlighted in this series of blog Posts.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many consumers are leery of designing and building a custom home and for many good reasons. As a professional building designer for over &lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt; years I have seen firsthand the benefits as well as the pitfalls experienced in the process. It doesn’t matter whether you have built a home before or where it is being built. These problems are almost universal. I will be posting a series of blogs to highlight the ups and downs as well as how to make the home design endeavor an enjoyable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;upcoming-posts-on-custom-home-design&quot;&gt;Upcoming Posts on Custom Home Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting the Perfect Site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selecting the Right Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Realistic Expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making Your Home Wishlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Preliminary Design Process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication and Trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pricing and Permitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Construction Begins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrapping It All Up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is much more than these issues to consider in the home building process. These seem to be the most common problems I encounter. Addressing these areas in a healthy fashion will minimize any possible pain when designing and building a new custom home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://saterdesign.com/pages/about-sater-design-collection&quot;&gt;Dan F Sater II FAIBD/CGP&lt;/a&gt; is the president of The Sater Group&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 20:33:07 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/06/08/custom-home-designs-rewards-challenges.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/06/08/custom-home-designs-rewards-challenges.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>International Project is taking Shape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A series of three Middle Eastern homes designed by &lt;strong&gt;The Sater Group&lt;/strong&gt; are taking shape in the desert. This international project is one of many by &lt;strong&gt;The Sater Group&lt;/strong&gt;. Each home is enclosed within its own distinct walled area. These homes are approximately &lt;strong&gt;21,000&lt;/strong&gt; square feet of living area for the main house. The homes are designed in a Mediterranean inspired architectural style with tiled roofs, stuccoed walls and hand carved stone accents. The homes open onto a large glass roofed pool area with outdoor living areas overlooking manicured gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/International-project-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View of Homes Pool Courtyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each estate has a complex that incorporates other support buildings including detached garage and entry gates. The homes walls are approximately &lt;strong&gt;22”&lt;/strong&gt; thick to provide protection from the harsh local climate. It has been a great privilege to design these homes and many others in distant locales. This demonstrates for us that creating unique luxury homes is appreciated regardless of climate or culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/International-project-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;International Home Designs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dramatic-entry-of-new-international-sater-group-designed-luxury-home&quot;&gt;Dramatic Entry of new International Sater Group designed luxury home.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/International-project-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homes outdoor Cabana&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;homes-outdoor-cabana&quot;&gt;Homes outdoor Cabana.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter where you are building your new home don’t hesitate to contact us for your design needs. We have designed luxury homes on every continent and countless countries. Let The Sater Group’s expertise with international projects assist you with your next home design. We love any challenge and especially in creating beautiful luxury homes for our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dramatic-arches-frame-grand-salon-entry&quot;&gt;Dramatic arches frame Grand Salon entry.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/International-project-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dramatic arches frame Grand Salon entry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 14:39:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/news/2015/04/13/international-project-is-taking-shape.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/news/2015/04/13/international-project-is-taking-shape.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
